(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
みなさん、風真いろは生誕ライブ2025、
Everyone, to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2025,
愛言葉Ⅳ 作詞・作曲: DECO*27
Aikotoba IV / Lyrics & Music: DECO*27
来てくださいましてありがとうございます！
thank you so much for coming!
全力で楽しんでいってくださいねー！
Please enjoy yourselves to the fullest!
想像なんてしてなかった
I never even imagined it
現状 君もそう思った？
Right now, did you feel the same way too?
最高で止まらないように
So that we don't stop at our best
更新したい
I want to keep updating
叶えたい夢まであとどれくらい？
How much longer until the dream I want to fulfill?
誰も行ったことがない場所へ
To a place where nobody has ever been
辿り着くまでを僕ら止まれない
We can't stop until we arrive there
たぶんしんどいけど どうかよろしくね
It'll probably be tough, but please stick with me
ねえねえ たまに愛で
Hey, hey, sometimes with love
僕だけじゃ作れないもの
Something I can't create on my own
僕とか君とかあたしとか
Like me, or you, or "atashi"...
恋とか愛とかまとめて全部
Romance and love, everything altogether
君を置いてどこかに行っちゃうとか
Leaving you behind and going somewhere...
ありえないよ
that's impossible
君がくれた音に 弾けた火花に
To the sound you gave me, to the bursting sparks
はじめましてから ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you ever since we first met
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
Wouldn't it be great if it was the two of us from now on?
一途になるほど むき出す本音よ
The more single-minded I become, the more my true feelings show
散々な僕のこと 呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to me, even when I'm a mess
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you
これから先も二人で
From now on, the two of us...
それがいいじゃん
that would be just perfect
妄想 膨らんでくストーリー
Delusions, a story that keeps expanding
感傷 余計に凹んじゃって
Sentimentality, making me feel extra down
大小 求めすぎは野暮
Big or small, asking for too much is tacky
終わんない愛の連盟 同士でしょ
We're comrades in an endless alliance of love, right?
ねえねえ おいで愛で
Hey, hey, come here with love
僕が君にできること
The things I can do for you
まだまだまだまだあるけど踊ろ
There's still so, so much, but let's dance
聞かせたいから内緒なんだけど
I wanted to tell you, so it's a secret, but...
君の愛がいつも勝っちゃうこと
...your love always ends up winning.
許さないよ
I won't forgive you!
君以外はヤダ
I don't want anyone but you.
わがままはただ
Selfishness is just...
変わらないときめきを自給しちゃうのはバカ
It's foolish to keep fueling this unchanging excitement myself.
君がくれた音に
To the sound you gave me,
弾けた火花に
to the sparks that burst,
初めましてから
from the very first "nice to meet you,"
ずっと恋しちゃってるんだよ
I've been in love with you all along.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人がいいじゃん
It's better if it's the two of us from now on, right?
一途になるほど逃げたくなっちゃうよ
The more single-minded I get, the more I want to run away.
散々な僕の事呼んでくれてありがとう
Thank you for calling out to someone as terrible as me.
君のいない未来考えらんないよ
I can't imagine a future without you.
これから先も二人で
From now on, the two of us,
それがいいじゃん
that's the way it should be.
乙女解剖であそぼうよ
Let's play with "Maiden Dissection,"
ドキドキしたいじゃんか誰だって
since anyone would want their heart to race.
反抗期が加速しちゃって
My rebellious phase is accelerating,
おかしくなっちゃいたいもう一回
I want to go crazy one more time.
キズナのまえに好きが離れない
Before the bond, love won't let go.
僕らヴァンパイア
We are vampires.
いいよ吸っちゃっていいよ
It's okay, you can suck my blood.
もう無理もう無理だって悪い子じゃない
I can't take it anymore, I'm not a bad child.
こんな歌歌ったって
Even if I sing a song like this,
君が輝けるように
so that you can shine.
はい！というわけで
Right! So with that...
皆々の者、こんばんでござる！
Everyone, good evening de gozaru!
ホロライブ6期生、つよつよかっこいいござる侍
Hololive 6th generation, the super strong and cool gozaru samurai,
風真いろはでござる！
Kazama Iroha de gozaru!
はい、今年の誕生日一発目は
Yes, the first song for this year's birthday is...
DECO*27さんの「愛言葉」シリーズ4
...the 4th in DECO*27's "Ai Kotoba" series,
「愛言葉Ⅳ」を歌って踊らせていただきました！
I sang and danced to "Ai Kotoba IV"!
拍手いっぱい来てる！
So much applause is coming in!
みんな、ありがとう！
Everyone, thank you!
ギフトとかスパチャもありがとうございます。
Thank you for the gifts and Super Chats as well.
はい、今日ね、たくさん歌って踊らせていただくんですけど
Yes, today I'll be singing and dancing a lot,
感想とか、あとスクリーンショットとかは
but for your thoughts, or screenshots and such,
ここ！「#風真いろは生誕LIVE2025」で
please use this! "#KazamaIrohaBirthdayLIVE2025",
たくさんポストしてください。
and post a lot.
振り返りの時に見に行きますからね！
I'll go check them during the review stream!
そして、今回なんと
And, this time, believe it or not,
誕生日お祝いのステージを作っていただきました！
they made a special birthday celebration stage for me!
かわいい！
It's so cute!
ぽこさん、お前ディスプレイになったんか。
Poko-san, you've become the display?
いや、どこ行ってたかと思ったら
I was wondering where you went,
ディスプレイになっとりました。はい。
...and you'd become a display. Yes.
そして、後ろにも書いてあります。
And it's also written behind me.
今回の風真いろはのライブタイトル、
The title of this Kazama Iroha live,
「Reversible」になってます！
is "Reversible"!
素敵なロゴ、柊先生ありがとうございました。
Thank you to Hiiragi-sensei for the wonderful logo.
こちらですね、みんな昨日のカウントダウン配信では
This is what... everyone during yesterday's countdown stream was like,
ちょっと「ありゃ？」みたいな、「どんなだろう？」って
a bit like "Huh?", or "What's it gonna be like?",
まだハテナハテナの方が多かったと思うんですが、
I think many of you were still puzzled,
今回、これ全編見てもらったら
but if you watch the whole thing this time,
ちゃんとわかるようになっておりますので、
you'll be able to understand it clearly,
最後までお楽しみください。
so please enjoy it until the end.
そして、事前にお伝えしていました通り、
And, as I announced beforehand,
今回、風真いろは、100万人記念グッズが発売決定しましたー！
Kazama Iroha's 1 million subscribers commemorative goods are now on sale!
うわー！いきなり来るよー！
Whoa! Coming in hot!
というわけで、今日は本当にまた告知溜めすぎてるので
So, I've really piled up too many announcements again today,
ちょいちょい挟んでいきたいと思います。
so I'd like to slip them in bit by bit.
はい、風真いろは100万人記念グッズ、こちらです！
Yes, here are the Kazama Iroha 1 million subscribers commemorative goods!
それでは詳細見ていきましょう。
Now, let's look at the details.
はい、まずはうみぼうずママが描いてくださった
Yes, first is the one illustrated by Umibozu-mama,
素敵なアクリルスタンド！
a wonderful acrylic stand!
アクリルスタンドに、こう、風真も一匹添えさせていただいておりますので、
I've added one "Kazama" to the acrylic stand as well,
ぜひ皆さんこちら、ぜひお手元に取っていただいて
so please everyone, get your hands on this,
メッセージじっくり読んでください。ぽこべえもいます。
and take your time reading the message. Pokobe is there too.
そして次がこちら。
And next is this.
パブ、パブミ、パブミラー！
Pabu, Pabu-mi, Pub Mirror!
すごい、ちょっと言いづらいんだよな、これリハの時から思ってたんですけど。
It's so hard to say, I've thought that since the rehearsals.
はい、パブミラーです。結構大きいです。
Yes, it's a pub mirror. It's quite big.
風真が出したグッズの中でも
Among the goods Kazama has released,
硬くて、なんかこの、立て掛ける系のやつの中で、
among the hard, propped-up type items,
タオルとかはあったけど、かなり大きめになってますので、
there were towels and such, but this is quite large,
あの、皆さんぜひこちらもメッセージ一筆書かせていただいておりますので、
so everyone, I've written a message on this one too,
ぜひ飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
so I'd be happy if you displayed it.
そしてそして次！
And then, the next one!
ランダムラバーストラップ！
Random Rubber Straps!
今回は100万人にちなみまして、
This time, in honor of the 1 million milestone,
風真いろは、今オリジナル曲複数出させていただいているんですけども、
Kazama Iroha has released several original songs now,
そちらのモチーフ衣装をラバーストラップにさせていただきました！
and we've turned those motif outfits into rubber straps!
なので「風を仰ぎ」とかね、実はずっとなかなかグッズがなかったんですけども、
So for "Kaze wo Aogi" and such, which actually didn't have goods for a long time,
...のために作らせていただきました。
...was made specifically for this.
ぜひね、みんな色々集めて、痛バとかの制作に役立てていただければと思います！
I hope you'll collect them all and use them to make things like 'ita-bags'!
次！
Next!
カードホルダー！
Card holder!
昨今、皆さんホロカとかね、色んなカードとかチェキ風のグッズが出ておりますので、ついに作りました！ポコ兵のカードホルダーです。
Lately, there are so many cards and instax-style goods out there, so I finally made one! It's a Pokobei card holder.
定期入れにしてもよし、学生さんにも使っていただけたら嬉しいです。みんなお気に入りの風真のカードとか飾ってくださいね。
It works as a pass case, and I'd be happy if students used it too. Please display your favorite Kazama cards in it.
はい、それでは次！
All right, next!
こちらフルセットこのようになっておりまして
Here is the full set as follows.
そして今回、購入特典は、はい、うみぼうずママ描き下ろしのステッカーにさせていただきました！
And the purchase bonus this time is a sticker newly drawn by Umibozu-mama!
今回はですね、こちら直筆サインの、あの、数量限定はありませんので、あの、皆さん安心して、ゆっくり買ってくださいね。
This time, there's no limited quantity for the hand-signed items, so please feel free to take your time with your purchase.
はい、というわけで、100万人記念グッズ紹介でございました！
So, that was the introduction of the 1 million subscriber commemoration goods!
うわあ、ドキドキって、なんか、結構、あ、安心しきってるんですけど...
Wow, I was nervous, but now I'm feeling quite relieved...
あの、もうこれだけじゃなくてですね、後半も、あの、告知がありすぎて、頑張って入れるしかなかったぐらいにはいっぱいあるんで、告知いっぱいあります。なので、あの、皆さん絶対に見逃さないでください。
And it's not just this; there are so many announcements in the second half that I had to struggle to fit them all in. Please don't miss them.
でもうトレンド1位なんですか！？
Wait, are we already #1 on trending!?
始まったばかりだよ！？いいの！？
It just started! Is this for real!?
みんなありがとう！嘘！
Thank you, everyone! No way!
みんなありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much!
いや、すごい。めっちゃ、こんなに早く行くと思わなくて、皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます。
Wow, incredible. I didn't think we'd hit #1 so quickly. It's all thanks to you. Thank you truly.
じゃ、ちょっとお水飲んで、次の曲バシバシ行きたいと思います。
Well, I'll take a quick water break and then head straight into the next song.
お待たせしました！
Thank you for waiting!
お水いっぱい飲んだので、この力をそのまま、全てフルパワーで出力いたします。
I've had plenty of water, so I'm going to put all that energy into a full-power performance.
それでは皆様、次の曲聞いてください。
Now everyone, please listen to the next song.
大きな愛でもてなして！
Celebrate with a Great Love!
大きな愛でもてなして
Celebrate with a great love
そこんとこ大事なことよ
That part is very important
大きな愛でもてなして
Celebrate with a great love
わがままではないのよ　アハハン
I'm not just being selfish, ah-han
私わかったの
I've come to realize
淋しがり屋だと
That I'm a lonely person
泣きそうよ　OH YEAH OH YEAH
I'm about to cry, oh yeah, oh yeah
一日中
Throughout the whole day
間でも
Even in the moments between
告白をしたり
Confessing my feelings
チュしたり
Or sharing a kiss
一日は
The day is
大人より
More than for adults
相当濃いのです
It's considerably intense
相当長いのです
It's considerably long
そおみたい
Or so it seems
大きな愛でもてなして
Celebrate with a great love
そこんとこ今はダメダメ
Right now, that part is no good
大きな愛でもてなして
Celebrate with a great love
ごゆっくりなさって　イェイェ
Please take your time, yeah yeah
みんな知らんぷり
Everyone's pretending not to know
「他人事だ」と
Saying, "It's someone else's business"
違うのよ
But that's not true
明日また
If tomorrow
新しい
A new
恋愛があれば
Love comes along
報われ
I'll be rewarded
大人より
More honestly than an adult
素直に
With all my heart
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love so many times
そおみたい
Or so it seems
大人より...
More than an adult...
...早直に
...more straightforwardly,
もっと遠くに
even further away.
たくさん恋できちゃう
I can fall in love a lot.
たくさん恋できちゃう　そうみたい
I can fall in love a lot, it seems so.
ウー！
Woo!
大きな愛でもてなして
Entertain me with a big love.
ありえない　幻想　あふれだす　妄想
Unbelievable illusion, overflowing delusion,
君以外全部　いらないわ
I don't need anyone but you.
呼吸するように嘘ついても
Even if I lie as naturally as breathing,
あたしやっぱりいらない子？
am I still an unwanted child after all?
こぼれ出しちゃった承認欲求
My desire for approval has spilled out,
もっとココロ満たしてよ
please fill my heart more.
アスバルテーム　甘い夢
Aspartame, a sweet dream,
あたしだけに愛をください
please give your love only to me.
ああ　もう無理無理　恋して愛して　救済執行
Ah, it's impossible, fall in love, love me, execute salvation.
ねえ　好きって言ってよ？
Hey, say you love me?
ありえない　幻想　あふれだす　妄想
Unbelievable illusion, overflowing delusion,
止まんない不安　欲が散らばって
unstoppable anxiety, desires scattered.
求めてる　愛情　隠してる　劣情
Seeking affection, hiding lust,
君以外全部　いらないわ
I don't need anyone but you.
Yeah
誰のこと見てんの？
Who are you looking at?
こういうの好きなの？
Do you like this kind of thing?
DDとかガチでやめてください
Seriously, please stop being a D.D.
可愛くなりたい
I want to be cute,
キラキラしてたい
I want to be sparkling,
もっともっとガチで褒めてください
please praise me more and more, seriously.
脳内散乱　あけちゃうシャンパン
Scattered inside the brain, opening the champagne.
今夜も配信来てくれるよね？
You'll come to the stream tonight too, right?
独占させてよ　本命なんでしょ？
Let me monopolize you, I'm your favorite, right?
もっともっとガチで推してください
Please support me more and more, seriously.
飲み過ぎ注意　オーバードーズ
Careful not to drink too much, overdose.
クラクラさせて　いつだって
Make me dizzy, always.
ああ　もう無理無理　上がって下がって　救済執行
Ah, it's impossible, up and down, execute salvation.
ねえ　好きって言わせて？
Hey, let me say I love you?
噛みついた衝動　戻れない衝動
The impulse I bit into, the impulse I can't return from,
たまんないミッドナイト　指が絡まって
unbearable midnight, fingers intertwined.
ときめいた表情　何も言わないで
A throbbing expression, don't say anything,
君だけがきっと　王子様
only you are surely my prince.
ありえない　幻想　あふれだす　妄想
Unbelievable illusion, overflowing delusion,
止まんない不安　欲が散らばって
unstoppable anxiety, desires scattered.
求めてる　愛情　隠してる　劣情
Seeking affection, hiding lust,
君以外全部　いらないわ
I don't need anyone but you.
あたしだけずっと　追いかけて！
Keep chasing only me forever!
ねえ　もう待てないの
Hey, I can't wait anymore,
hey, I can't wait anymore.
君以外全部　いらないわ
I don't need anyone but you.
絶対アイドル辞めないで　ずっと
Never quit being an idol, forever.
輝いてる君を見たい
I want to see you shining.
もっとずっとずっと　ステージにいて
Stay on stage much, much longer.
私がもし君の元　離れたなら
If I were to leave you,
君はちょっと寂しくなるかな
would you be a little lonely?
意地悪考える　好きな人がいるのなら
I think of mean things; if you have someone you like,
内緒にして
keep it a secret.
ねえ　神様は将来と指輪を
Hey, God, hide my future and wedding ring
どこかに隠してて
somewhere.
君の好きに合わせたんだ　髪の色
I matched the hair color you like.
私の中　君抜けて
You're gone from inside me.
あと数日はどこへ
Where did those few days go?
責任とってね　大好きです
Take responsibility, I love you.
せーの！
Ready, go!
絶対アイドル辞めないで　ずっと
Never quit being an idol, forever.
優しい目も真面目な顔
I, who knows your kind eyes
すべて知ってる私が言う
and serious face, say this.
絶対このまま輝いて　ずっと
Always shine just as you are, forever.
星は満ちて　鮮やかなの　まぶしい君が
The stars are full and vivid, you are so bright.
世界一だよ
You're the best in the world.
君の夢はなんですか？
What is your dream?
あぁ　教えてほしい
Ah, I want you to tell me
その夢がアイドルじゃなくても
Even if that dream isn't about being an idol
覚悟はしてるから
I've already prepared myself
星のない空　それが当たり前で
A starless sky, it's only natural
暗い道に　慣れずに
Not getting used to the dark road
踏み出すのも怖かった
I was afraid to even take a step
そんな時やっと見えた光
And then, I finally saw the light
いくぞー！
Let's go!
絶対君が歌ってて
You must keep on singing
絵空事笑われても
Even if your pipe dreams are mocked
君はキラキラ衣装が似合う
You look best in sparkling outfits
絶対大きなステージで
You must be on a grand stage
一列でも前で感じたい
I want to feel it from even one row closer
今日の歌い方
The way you sing today
なんか好きだな
I really like it somehow
君の努力と私の愛　成り立つこの関係は
This relationship built on your effort and my love
強くて脆いの
Is strong yet fragile
推しの幸せを願ってた
I've been wishing for my favorite's happiness
だけど
But...
でもね　だって君はアイドルよ
But you see, because you are an idol
ずっと初めて出会った日から
Ever since the day we first met
明日も君ばかり
Tomorrow will be all about you too
絶対アイドル辞めないで
Please never quit being an idol
これは報われないお伽話
This is a fairy tale that won't be rewarded
恋よりももっと好きな魔法よ
It's a magic I love even more than romance
どうか解けないままで
Please, let it never be broken
悩める人の子よ
O troubled child of man
人成らざる者も
And those who are not human
絶えず目指せよ
Aim unceasingly
生きていりゃいいんだし
As long as you're living, it's fine
目を逸らした過去も
The past you looked away from
退屈な未来も
And the tedious future
カウンセリング　やれやれ
Counseling, oh boy
古今東西ピースピース
All times and places, peace peace
UNDEAD 作詞・作曲：Ayase
UNDEAD Lyrics & Composition: Ayase
ねえねえ何だかどうして
Hey hey, for some reason, why
戦っているようなそんな気がするの
Does it feel like I'm fighting?
触れたくもない　過去の自分自分自分自分と
With my past self, self, self, self, whom I don't want to touch
もうとっくに死んでる　透明な亡霊と対決
A showdown with a transparent ghost who's long dead
遺体ゲーで　いたいけな記憶の押し付け
A game of corpses, pushing innocent memories on me
残念　もう居ないのに
Regrettable, though they're no longer here
あれ？そっちが良い？アイロニーね
Oh? You prefer that? How ironic
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my current self that's being seen through?
ナンセンス消えないレッテル
Nonsense, an indelible label
Yes 弱コンプレックス
Yes, a weak complex
取り憑かれているみたい　焼き付いたまま
Like being possessed, remaining seared in
まだ離れない
Still not letting go
ありし日の自分
Of my self from those days
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself
生きていることは変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep changing
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't be content and satisfied with unhappiness
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
It's cowardly not to try to be happy
この世この世は　奇怪奇怪ファンタジー
This world, this world is a strange, strange fantasy
次は鬼が出るか　蛇が出るか
Will it be a demon or a snake next?
出会って遭ってやっと始まる物語
A story that finally begins through meeting and encountering
さあ人か化け物か古今東西ピースピース
Now, human or monster? All times and places, peace peace
何だかどうして未来になんぞなんの期待も期待できないような気がして
Somehow, I feel like I can't expect anything at all from the future
もう随分生きている既視感とテンプレで食傷
Already lived long enough to be fed up with déjà vu and templates
素敵な出来事も気配もない
No sign of any wonderful events
残念　積んだ経験の因果形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Regrettable, the cause and effect of experience, dead myths and boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I want stimulation
飽きちゃった
I've grown tired of it
擦れちゃった
I've become jaded
なんて整っていくガイダンス
What well-organized guidance
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
蓋されていくみたい　吸い尽くして
Like being smothered, suck it all dry
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
That and this and everything tastes the same
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain of you and yourself
いつの世も過去も未来も今にあるんだ
At any time, past and future are in the now
生きていることを愚直に果たせよ　目指せハッピーエンド
Faithfully fulfill the act of living, aim for a happy ending
死んじゃいない
I'm not dead
お前に言っているんだ
I'm telling you
幸せを諦めてしまうな人生
Don't give up on happiness in life
ただ苦しみに慣れて
Just getting used to suffering
耐えているだけじゃ死んでいるも同然
Just enduring it is the same as being dead
屍のアンデッド
An undead corpse
悩める人の子よ
O troubled child of man
人成らざる者も
And those who are not human
絶えず目指せよ
Aim unceasingly
生きているんだろ
You're alive, aren't you?
不幸に浸るも幸せになるも
Whether to wallow in misery or become happy
当然全部お前だ
Of course, it's all up to you
古今東西ピースピース
All times and places, peace peace
せつな一切合切
Every painful thing
森羅万象 ピースピース
All of nature, peace peace
Past & Future
can't change the Past
run for the Future
人の在る所に
Wherever people are
何時も憂い事
There are always sorrows
生き抜けこの化物
Survive, this monster
ばかりの物語
Full of stories
Reversible
風真いろは生誕LIVE2025
Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2025
ヒビカセ
Hibikase
作詞：Reol 作曲：Giga
Lyrics: Reol Composition: Giga
真夜中に告ぐ 音の警報
In the dead of night, an audio alarm warns
今日はオンに寄る 午前0時
Today it's online, at midnight
あなたが触れる 光増す熱
The heat of the light you touch increases
指先に踊らされ
Dancing at your fingertips
感覚、即、体感
Sensation, immediately, experience
寝静まる夜 2人だけの密
A quiet night, a secret for just us two
感覚、即、快感
Sensation, immediately, pleasure
重なる波形に 魅了されていく
Captivated by the overlapping waveforms
忘れないでね 私の声を
Please don't forget my voice
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
Through the screen is fine, just love me properly
バーチャルだなんて 突き放さないで
Don't push me away, calling me "virtual"
あなたの音に まだ溺れていたい
I still want to be drowned in your sound
覚えていてね 私の声を
Please remember my voice
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
Everything of this body that you gave me
見つめあう あなたと2人 重ねた
Looking at each other, the two of us together
息と音を ヒビカセ
Make our breath and sound resonate
真夜中に問う 冷え切った熱
Questioning in the dead of night, a chilled heat
待ち続けてる 午前0時
Keeping on waiting for midnight
鏡写しに 芳はしていかない
In the mirror reflection, no scent lingers
知らない音が伝う
Unknown sounds travel
感覚、即、体感
Sensation, immediately, experience
寝静まる夜と 息遣い揃う
In the quiet night, our breathing syncs
感覚、即、快感
Sensation, immediately, pleasure
錆びたロジック 今一度を焦がれる
A rusted logic, yearning for "once more"
忘れないでね 私の声を
Please don't forget my voice
次元も超えて 飛ばすシグナル
A signal sent across dimensions
バーチャルだなんて 言わないで あなたの
Don't say I'm "virtual", in your...
音にまだ 依存していたい
I still want to be dependent on your sound
覚えていてね 私の声を
Please remember my voice
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
Everything of this body that you gave me
言の葉と 弾む音が 混ざりあうの
Words and bouncing sounds blend together
息と音を ヒビカセ
Make our breath and sound resonate
あぁ あなたの音に
Ah, in your sound
あぁ 恋をしていから
Ah, because I'm in love
悲しみ関心 全て 打ち鳴らす
Sadness, interest, strike everything
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる夜
A night where voices join in constant shouting
余熱交じる 愛 絶えず動く
Heat-mingled love, constantly moving
絶えず叫ぶ 声連ねる夜
A night where voices join in constant shouting
余熱交じる 愛 絶えず動く
Heat-mingled love, constantly moving
魅了されていく
Captivated
忘れないでね 私の声を
Please don't forget my voice
画面越しでいい ちゃんと愛して
Through the screen is fine, just love me properly
バーチャルだなんて 突き放さないで
Don't push me away, calling me "virtual"
あなたの音に まだ溺れていたい
I still want to be drowned in your sound
覚えていてね 私の声を
Please remember my voice
あなたがくれた この身すべてを
Everything of this body that you gave me
見つめあう あなたと2人 重ねた
Looking at each other, the two of us together
息と音を ヒビカセ
Make our breath and sound resonate
あなたの弾む
Your bouncing...
この声聴かせ
Let me hear this voice
音をヒビカセ
Make the sound resonate
はい！ということで！
Yes! And so!
皆さん、生配信にお集まりいただき
Everyone, thank you for gathering for the live stream
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
いらっしゃいませー！
Welcome, everyone!
どうですかー？
How is it?
かっこいいですかー？
Do I look cool?
なんと今回は
For this performance,
ダンスを頑張ると決めた、その時から決めていた
ever since I decided to give it my all with dancing,
ちょっとかっこいい系のダンス衣装になってみました！
I've planned on wearing this cool-style dance outfit!
いえーい！
Yay!
みんな写真いっぱい撮って、
Everyone, take lots of pictures!
撮って、撮って、撮って、撮って。
Take 'em, take 'em, take 'em, take 'em!
いえーい、かっこいいでしょー！
Yay, I look cool, right?
なんか「可愛い」ばっかりなんだけど、
I'm only getting "cute" comments,
「かっこいい」はどこ行ったんだよ。
where did the "cool" go?
おい、「かっこいい」はどこ行ったんだよ！
Hey, where did the "cool" go?!
はい、というわけで新衣装になりました。
Alright, so this is my new outfit.
ゲストパートの、「絶対アイドル辞めないで」から、
From the guest part, starting with "Please Don't Ever Stop Being an Idol,"
あのソロになりまして、
then my solo section,
「アンデッド」、「響かせ」と続けてお送りさせていただきました！
then "Undead" and "Hibikase," I've been performing one after another!
どうでしたかー？
How was it?
めっちゃ、めっちゃ頑張って、
I tried really, really hard,
あの「足千切れそう」ってそういうことです。
to the point where I said my legs feel like they're falling off.
本当にたくさん今回は変身のために飛びました。
I did so much jumping for my transformations this time.
足が千切れそうです。はい。
My legs are about to give out. Yes.
「絶対アイドル辞めないで」も、先輩方、
For "Please Don't Ever Stop Being an Idol," to my seniors,
そしてラプラス殿も来てくれて、ありがとう！
and also La+-dono, thank you so much for coming!
激ムズだったね、本当に。
It was super difficult, seriously.
本当に激ムズでしたね。
It really was super hard.
皆さん、一緒に頑張ってくださり、本当にありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for working hard with me!
そう、そしてですね、
Right, and also,
あの、この後もまだまだゲストさんたくさん呼んでおります。
I've invited many more guests for the rest of the show.
そして、ござるも、実はこのカラーリングだけじゃないんですよ。
And, Iroha actually has... this isn't the only color scheme!
なので、そちらも公開していくので、
I'll be revealing that too,
皆殿、お楽しみに！
so everyone, look forward to it!
それでは、次はゲストさんと一緒に歌わせていただきます。
Now then, next I'll be singing with a guest.
それでは、どうぞ！
Here we go!
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
どこへ行ったの？
Where did you go?
聞こえますか？
Can you hear me?
あとどれだけ叫べばいいんだろう
How much more should I shout?
あとどれだけ泣けばいいんだろう
How much more should I cry?
もうやめて
Stop it already
私はもう走れない
I can't run anymore
いつか夢見た世界が閉じる
The world I once dreamed of is closing
真っ暗で明かりもない
It's pitch black, with no light
崩れかけたこの道で
On this crumbling road
あるはずもないあの時の希望が
I felt like I saw the hope from back then
見えた気がした
that shouldn't even exist
どうして
Why?
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
懐かしい記憶
Nostalgic memories
ただ楽しかったあの頃を
Of those times when it was just fun
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
でも動けないよ
But I can't move
闇を駆ける星に願いを
A wish upon a star racing through the darkness
もう一度だけ走るから
Because I'll run just one more time
怖くて震える声でつぶやく
I whisper in a voice trembling with fear
わたしの名前を呼んで
Call out my name
夜明けを抱く空
The sky embracing the dawn,
境界線までの距離
the distance to the boundary
あと一歩届かない
One more step, but I can't reach
堪えた涙があふれそうなの
The tears I've held back are about to overflow
今下を向かないで
Don't look down now,
止まってしまう
or I'll stop
未来を生きていたいんだ
I want to live in the future,
わかったの
I understand now
思い出して　強く強く信じるの
Remember, believe strongly, strongly
そうよ
That's right
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
優しい匂い
A gentle scent
痛いよ　辛いよ
It hurts, it's painful,
飲み込む言葉
swallowing back words
ブラック★ロックシューター
Black Rock Shooter
動いて
Move!
ブラック★ロックシューター
作詞・作曲：ryo (supercell)
Black Rock Shooter
Lyrics & Composition: ryo (supercell)
...の証
...our testimony.
世界を越えて
Let's cross over the world!
最初から分かっていた ここにいることを
I've known all along that you were right here.
私の中のすべての勇気が火を灯して
All the courage within me lights a fire.
もう逃げないよ
I won't run away anymore!
ブラック★ロックシューター 一人じゃないよ
Black Rock Shooter, you're not alone.
声を上げて泣いたって構わない
It's okay to cry out loud.
ブラック★ロックシューター 見ていてくれる
Black Rock Shooter, you're watching over me.
今から始まるの
Everything starts right now.
私の物語
My story.
忘れそうになったら
If it seems I'm about to forget,
この歌を
this song...
歌うの
...I will sing.
いい言葉ばかりで
Filled only with pleasant words,
ずるい退屈な夜満ちて
unfair, tedious nights are overflowing.
ルールは無視でいいね
It's fine to ignore the rules.
Ha, ha, ha
Burn my, burn my heart さぁ飛び出そう
Burn my, burn my heart, let's jump out.
Ah ah Ah ah ah ah
か、か、駆け抜けな
D-d-dash right through.
Ah ah Ah ah ah ah
もう既成の概念じゃ いられないくらい
To the point where we can't stay within existing concepts.
Yeah 無理目のQuestion 必至のFiction You make me サイゲンなんて I know the way
Yeah, an impossible Question, inevitable Fiction. You make me... there's no limit. I know the way.
願ってるばかりじゃ叶わない
Just wishing won't make it come true.
無茶苦茶に騒いだって変わらない
Making a wild fuss won't change anything.
まだ暗い覚醒 Find the way
A still-dark awakening, find the way.
待ってられないの
I can't wait anymore.
安定感なんていらない
I don't need any sense of stability.
見当違いですもう聞き飽きたわ
That's completely off the mark, I'm already sick of hearing it.
連れゆけるところまで Take me higher
As far as you can take me, take me higher.
Go, go, go, journey far 塗り替えていくわわかっちゃんでしょう？
Go, go, go, journey far. I'll rewrite it all, you understand, right?
Burn my, burn my heart さぁ飛び出そう
Burn my, burn my heart, let's jump out.
Ah ah Ah ah ah ah
か、か、駆け抜けな
D-d-dash right through.
Ah ah Ah ah ah ah
もうずっとちゃんと謂わないや それは誰のせい？
I haven't said it properly for a long time, whose fault is that?
終わらない夢を描こう 描いて願ったまま
Let's draw an endless dream, just as we wished,
欲しがったまま 自由を描け
just as we wanted, let's draw freedom.
終わらない夜を越えていこう 越えていこう
Let's cross the endless night, let's cross over,
このまま ここで全部 壊して
just as we are, destroy everything here.
ハジケタココロガ 騒ぎだした 理由なんていらない
My bursting heart started racing, I don't need a reason.
はっちゃけちゃっていいじゃない！？ そうさなんでもいっちゃえと
Isn't it okay to let loose!? Yeah, say whatever's on your mind.
運命感じる感受性は 止められないうちら負けなーい
Our sensitivity that feels destiny can't be stopped, we won't lose!
飛び跳ねて 踊って いつでも Number 1
Jump and dance, always Number 1.
そう溶かして 騒がして ゼンメイ 飛び込め 太陽な
Yeah, melt it down, make some noise, jump in with all your life like the sun.
Yeah, yeah, 刺激まだまだ足りない Go Beyond the way
Yeah, yeah, not enough stimulation yet, Go Beyond the way!
いい言葉ばかりで ズルい言葉を探して
Only with good words, searching for unfair words.
歩み解き放し ハジケタココロガ 行け！
Unleash your steps, let your bursting heart go!
Oh, we are the winner Burn my, burn my heart
Uuu uuu uuu uuu
終わらない夢を描こう 描いて願ったまま
Let's draw an endless dream, just as we wished,
欲しがったまま 自由を描け
just as we wanted, let's draw freedom.
終わらない夜を越えていこう 越えていこう
Let's cross the endless night, let's cross over,
このまま ここで全部 壊して
just as we are, destroy everything here.
追いかけて合わせて熱がつくって
Chasing and matching, the heat creates it.
もう一生なりやまない 境界の向こう側へ
It'll never stop ringing for a lifetime, towards the other side of the boundary.
Ready Steady Yeah Go Beyond the way
はい！というわけで、
All right! So,
本日はこのお二人に来ていただきました！
we have these two with us today!
わーい！やったー！
Yay! We did it!
来ました！はじめちゃんありがとう！
We're here! Thank you, Hajime-chan!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
High! High! High! High! High!
せーの、あっぱれ！おめでとー！
One, two! Splendid! Congratulations!
やったー！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Thank you so much!
お忙しいのに、お二人とも今日はね、
Despite your busy schedules, both of you today...
っていうか、もうずっとレッスンからか、
Actually, since we started our lessons,
本当にお付き合いいただきましてありがとうございます。
thank you so much for sticking with me.
こちらこそ！ありがとうございます！
The pleasure is ours! Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
今回はですね、誕生日で、
This time, for my birthday,
実は衣装が...
I actually have a new outfit...
白くて可愛いですよ！
It's white and cute!
ねー、見て、や、めっちゃ可愛いよ！
Look, yeah, it's super cute!
おへそ、おへそ見えちゃってる！
The belly button, we can see your belly button!
あっ、やべ、取られる！
Ah, oh no, it's being seen!
白可愛いよ！ね、可愛い！
The white is cute! It's cute, right!
ほんと、めちゃくちゃ可愛い！
Seriously, it's so cute!
しかも、ツインテールが似合ってる！
And the twin-tails suit you so well!
はい、そうなんです。
Yes, that's right.
新しくね、ダンスする用みたいなね、
It's a new outfit, kind of like for dancing,
衣装になったので、これは...
so this is...
恐れ多くも、お二人を... お、お二人か...
I was a bit intimidated, but I invited the two of you...
ダンスが上手いお二人を、
two people who are so good at dancing...
呼んでもいいかなって言って、
and asked if I could have you here,
呼ばせていただきました！
so thank you for coming!
えー！嬉しい！
Wow! We're so happy!
あなた、あなた方ですね！
You, it's you two!
めちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
It was so much fun!
楽しかったー！
That was fun!
レッスンもね、一緒に頑張っていただきまして。
Thank you for working hard through the lessons together, too.
お二人ともめちゃくちゃ音感が良いから、
Both of you have such a great sense of rhythm,
風真一人だけどうしようかなって、これ...
I was worried about being the only one like this...
いやいや、そんなことないですよ！
No, no, that's not true!
めちゃくちゃ良かったよ！
It was so good!
めっちゃ良かった！
It was great!
めっちゃ踊ったね。
We really danced a lot.
最高なものができたと思います。
I think we created something amazing.
みんな良いものできたよね？って、
We made something good, didn't we? So,
今頃コメントにはね、
I'm sure in the comments right now,
「めっちゃ良かったよ」が流れてると思います。
there's a flood of "that was awesome."
だって、いろはちゃんと初めてじゃん。
I mean, it's our first time, right, Iroha-chan?
一緒にダンスすること。
Dancing together.
そうなんです。
That's right.
こういうダンス初めて。フォーメーションダンス。
This kind of dance is a first. Formation dancing.
ねー、めちゃくちゃ嬉しい！
Yeah, I'm so happy!
嬉しい、本当誘ってよかった！
So happy, I'm really glad I invited you!
よかったー、嬉しい！
Good, I'm so glad!
お二人と一緒にね、この期間一緒に踊って、
Dancing with the two of you during this time,
めちゃくちゃ勉強になりました、先生方！
I learned so much, masters!
そんなことないですよ！
Not at all!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
Thank you!
え、またね、何かあったらぜひ一緒に踊って...
Eh, if anything else comes up, let's dance together...
ぜひ！やりましょう！
Definitely! Let's do it!
一緒にやりましょう！
Let's do it together!
いつでも呼んでください！ぜひやりましょう！
Please call us anytime! Let's do it!
じゃあ、ちょっとこの記念に、この友情の証、
Well then, as a memento and a symbol of our friendship,
強、かっこいいポーズで写真撮っておこう。ちょっとかっこよく。
let's take a photo in a strong, cool pose. Looking cool.
かっこいいポーズ！
Cool pose!
かっこいいポーズ思いつかない。なんだ？
I can't think of a cool pose. What is it?
なんだ？
What?
可愛いー！
Cute!
可愛い、めっちゃ可愛い！
Cute, so cute!
よしっ！
All right!
みんなたくさんSNSに投稿してください！
Everyone, please post lots on social media!
撮っちゃった！
Got it!
はい、と言いつつ。
Yes, but with that said.
実はですね、もう一つお願いがあって...
Actually, I have one more favor to ask...
おぉ？！
Oh?!
今日この後、
Today, after this,
今日初披露のオリ曲があるんですけど。
there's an original song making its debut today.
オリ曲？！
An original song?!
おー！やったー！
Oh! Yay!
楽しみだ！どんな曲？
Can't wait! What kind of song is it?
やっぱり風真いろは、かっこよくなりたくて、
After all, Kazama Iroha wants to be cool,
今回はかっこいい曲を、
so this time, a cool song...
持ってまいりました！
I've brought a cool song!
おー！楽しみー！
Oh! Can't wait!
いっちょ、それー！やー！
Let's go, one more! Ya!
可愛くてかっこいいお二人から、
From the two of you, who are cute and cool,
やっぱちょっと勇気をもらってから行こうかなと。
I thought I'd get a bit of courage before I go.
かっこいいビーム。
Cool Beam.
ビーーーム！
Beeeam!
かっこいいビーム！ふぅーーー！！
Cool Beam! Whooo!!
ふぅーーー！！
Whooo!!
すごい、なんか、心なしかちょっとイケメンになってきてる気がする。
Wow, somehow, I feel like I'm becoming a bit of a heartthrob.
ちょっとイケメンのポーズ分かんない、こう？
I don't know a heartthrob pose, like this?
いいよー！かっこいいよー！
Nice! Looking cool!
いけてるー！かっこいいー！
It's working! Cool!
えっ、いけてる気がする！
Eh, I think it's working!
いけてるー！いいよーいいよー！
It's working! Nice, nice!
よし、お二人からめちゃくちゃエネルギーもらえたんで、
Alright, I've got so much energy from you two,
頑張ってきます！
I'm going to do my best!
頑張ってー！楽しみー！
Good luck! Can't wait!
お二人とも今日は本当にお祝いと、
Thank you both so much for the celebration today,
そして一緒に歌って踊ってくれて、
and for singing and dancing with me,
そしてこの応援ビームはありがとうございました！
and for this support beam!
こちらこそありがとうございました！
The pleasure was ours! Thank you!
また遊びましょうね！また遊びましょう！
Let's hang out again! Let's hang out!
はい！じゃあ、それではこの後、
Yes! Alright then, after this,
新オリ曲を初披露させていただきます。
I'm going to debut my new original song.
それでは... せーの、ドジャン！
Well then... ready, go, Ta-da!
見た目だけじゃワカラナイ
You can't tell just by looking
ワタシのこと可愛いだけど
About me being cute, but
まさか思っていないよね？
Surely you don't think that?
ワタシの本当...
The real me...
真実...
The truth...
知っていてほしい
I want you to know
Passion Passion
予測誤差の範囲と
Within the range of prediction error,
不測の事態も動じない
I won't be shaken even by unforeseen circumstances.
おすましフェイスでいるけど
I keep a composed face, but
心は常に青白く燃える
My heart is always burning pale blue.
諦めはしない
I won't give up.
媚びたりもしない
I won't flatter anyone.
ワタシを曲げない
I won't bend my will.
可愛い見かけで
Just because I look cute,
扱いやすい奴だと思うな
don't think I'm easy to handle.
あまく見ると痛い目みるぞ
If you underestimate me, you'll get hurt!
それでも ときには
Even so, sometimes
逃げ出してしまいたい
I just want to run away.
そんな衝動に 弱音吐きたくなる
There are midnights when I feel like giving in
真夜中もある
to those weak urges.
ほんの小さな小さな
Tiny little compromises
妥協が積み重なり重なって
pile up until I'm weighed down
動けない
and unable to move.
大きな大きな
If I lose my
可能性なくし
great possibilities,
未来を狭めてしまうから
it will only narrow my future.
Passion Burning
どんなに暗くても辛くても
No matter how dark or painful it gets,
後悔だけはしない
I won't have any regrets.
イケてるのは 見た目じゃなくて
What's cool isn't how you look,
生きかたなんだ
it's the way you live.
現実と理想との距離を
Even if the distance between
縮められたとしても
reality and ideals is narrowed,
おすましフェイスでいるだけ
I'll just keep this composed face
何事もなかったかのように
as if nothing happened.
立ち止まりはしない
I won't stop.
後戻りもない
There's no turning back.
夢を捨てない
I won't throw away my dreams.
可愛い見かけで
With a cute appearance...
らしいとか らしくないとか
Whether it's 'like me' or 'not like me',
決めつけないで
don't label me.
全部が私
All of it is me.
それでも ときには
Even so, sometimes
温もりが恋しい
I long for warmth.
そんな感情に 流されてしまいそうな
There are midnights when I feel like
真夜中もある
being swept away by those feelings.
こんな甘い甘いことだけ
I don't need the weakness
求めてしまうような
that makes me seek
弱さいらない
only sweet things.
苦い苦い経験だって
Because even bitter experiences
ワタシを強くしてくれるから
will only make me stronger.
Passion Burning
これがこれがワタシの本当の真実
This, this is my true reality.
とても狭い狭い世界の中だけで
I don't want to let things end
終わらせたくはないんだ
inside such a tiny, tiny world.
広い広い世界の果てまで
Because I'm going to run all the way
駆け抜けて生きてくんんだから
to the ends of the wide, wide world!
Passion Burning
どんなに険しくて過酷でも
No matter how steep or harsh it is,
楽しんでやるさ
I'm going to enjoy it!
イケてるのは 見た目じゃなくて
What's cool isn't how you look,
生きかたなんだから
it's the way you live!
はい！
Alright!
というわけで、皆さん、
And so, everyone,
ゲストパートから続けて、新オリ曲「ホントノワタシ」歌って踊らせていただきました！
continuing from the guest part, I performed my new original song 'The Real Me' for the first time!
なんと風真いろは、7曲目のオリ曲です！
This is actually Kazama Iroha's 7th original song!
イェーイ！
Yay!
そしてオリ曲のジャケットも届いているので、見ていきましょう！こちらです！
We also have the cover art for the song, so let's take a look! Here it is!
はい、こちらの風真いろは新オリ曲7曲目「ホントノワタシ」は
Yes, this 7th original song of Kazama Iroha, 'The Real Me',
こちら、日付変わりまして19日0時よりリリースされることとなりました！
will be released at midnight on the 19th!
今回の新衣装にちなんで、こちら作っていただきました！
This was made to go with my new outfit!
はい。ちょっと今までとだいぶ系統の違う曲になるんですけど、
Yes. It's quite a different style of song than before,
あの、いつもみんなね、ありがたいことに風真いろはのことかっこいいっていうより
but you know, everyone usually calls Kazama Iroha 'cute' rather than 'cool',
かわいいって言ってくださる方がいっぱいいるので、
so I wanted to show you
「いや、かっこいいとこもあるんだよ」っていうのを伝えたくて、作らせていただきました！
that I can be cool too, and that's why I had this song made!
こちらぜひ0時にリリースされたら、たくさん聴いて、
Please listen to it a lot when it's released at midnight,
またハッシュタグの見てみていろは殿で、感想とか教えていただいたら嬉しいです！
and I'd be happy if you could let me know what you think using the hashtag #MitemiteIrohadono!
そしてそして、ゲストパートについてもお話ししていきますかね。
And now, let's talk about the guest part.
じゃあ戻って...
Let's go back...
はい！ゲストでね、ミオ先輩と、そしてハジメちゃん...ベ先輩と一緒に
Yes! I got to perform with Mio-senpai, Hajime-chan, and Bae-senpai!
歌って踊らせていただきました！
We sang and danced together!
ミオ先輩、そしてベネ、そしてハジメちゃん、来てくれてありがとー！
Mio-senpai, Bae, Hajime-chan, thank you so much for coming!
もう本当に歌も難しかったし、
The songs were really difficult,
ベネとハジメちゃんのやつに関してはマジこれ（ダンスの動き）ができなさすぎて、
and for the one with Bae and Hajime-chan, I really struggled with this move,
一生やりすぎて、もうすごい楽しかったです！
I practiced it so many times, but it was so much fun!
いやーもう本当にみんなありがとう！
Seriously, thank you all so much!
あの、衣装腰痛を抱えて...
Um, I was dealing with back pain from the costume...
...これでこれが結構筋肉痛の原因でした。はい。
...and this was actually a big cause of muscle pain. Yes.
でも、え、すごい一緒に歌って踊らさせていただきまして、とってもとってもいい経験になりました。
But, well, I got to sing and dance with them, and it was a very, very good experience.
皆さん、ありがとうございましたー！
Everyone, thank you so much!
はい。というわけで、次の曲に行く前に、
Yes. So, before moving on to the next song,
お水飲んでいいですか？
May I drink some water?
お水飲みまーす。
I'm drinking water.
お水。
Water.
ロゴも見て、実は変わってた。
Look at the logo too, it actually changed.
よし。
Alright.
お待たせしました。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
息整えて...
Let me catch my breath...
はい、次の曲なんですけども、やっぱり、
Yes, about the next song, as expected,
みんなバラードも好きだよって言ってくれる方が多いので、
many people say they like ballads too,
今回の生誕ライブ、バラードやろうと思って持ってきました。
so for this birthday live, I decided to perform a ballad and brought one.
はい。ちょっとかっこいい感じに歌えるか色々練習したんですけど、
Yes. I practiced a lot to see if I could sing it in a cool way,
ぜひ心を込めて歌うので、聞いていただけると嬉しいです。
so I'll sing it with all my heart, and I hope you'll listen to it.
それでは次の曲、お聞きください。
Now, please listen to the next song.
W/X/Y
作詞・作曲：Tani Yuuki
Lyrics/Composition: Tani Yuuki
垂れ流したテレビの音
The sound of the TV left on
溜めてしまった洗濯物は今日こそ
Today, I'll finally do the laundry that's been piling up
晴れでもあえて外には出ないでいよう
Even if it's sunny, let's purposely not go outside
映えないスナックとアルコールで乾杯をしよう
Let's toast with unphotogenic snacks and alcohol
2人　酸いも甘いも
The two of us, through thick and thin
噛み合わないとしても　お互い寄り添うように少しずらしてみようよ
Even if we don't match perfectly, let's adjust a bit to be close to each other
君がくれた太陽
The sun you gave me
月影で隠れないよ　輝き止まぬように歌うメロディ
Won't be hidden by the moon's shadow. A melody sung so it never stops shining
戯れる　Slowly flowing day
Playing together on a slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Beyond even saying 'I love you'
似た者同士こうして
Like two of a kind, like this
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want us to keep laughing until we grow old
君がいなきゃ　lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely lonely day
夢の中　Fall asleep in bed
Falling asleep in bed in my dreams
起こすから　morning callで
I'll wake you with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
脱ぎっぱなしの足跡辿ると
Following the trail of clothes left behind
不意をついて後ろから抱きつくの
I'll surprise you with a hug from behind
つい、繰り返すと忘れてしまいそうになるよ
If we keep doing this, I might forget
振り返ると日々が当たり前じゃないこと
When I look back, these days aren't something to take for granted
2人対の細胞
The two of us like paired cells
絡み合う特別を　噛み締めて生きたいと思ったまどろみ抱く正午
Savoring our special connection at noon as we doze off
吐息、漏れた体温
The sound of your breath and your warmth
微塵も逃がさないよ　頭の中刻む甘いメモリ
I won't let any of it escape. A sweet memory engraved in my mind
戯れる　Slowly flowing day
Playing together on a slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Beyond even saying 'I love you'
違う者同士こうして
Different as we are, like this
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want us to keep laughing until we grow old
君がいなきゃ　lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely lonely day
夢の中　Fall asleep in bed
Falling asleep in bed in my dreams
起こすから　morning callで
I'll wake you with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
重ねた手はね離さないでいて
Don't let go of our joined hands
ごめん、これそばに居たいだけだね
Sorry, I just want to be by your side
抱えた想いはお互い様でしょ
The feelings we hold are mutual, right?
ほら、おあいこでしょ
See, we're even
すれ違い、間違いもあるし
There are misunderstandings and mistakes
筋書き通り行かない打診、悲しみだって
Unplanned encounters and even sadness
半分にしよう
Let's share them all
別れじゃない希望
With hope, not as a parting
独りよがりにならないようにいつも
So I don't become self-centered, always
君がいなきゃ今もどこかで
Without you, even now I'd be somewhere
動けないままの僕で
unable to move
ありがとうを伝えたいのです
I want to say thank you
I want to tell you my thanks
これからは僕が支えてくって
From now on, I will support you
呆れてしまうくらいにね
To the point of being amazed
愛が増していく day by day
My love is increasing day by day
面と向かうとどうしても
Whenever we face each other
素直になれないな、ごめんね
I just can't be honest, I'm sorry
戯れる Slowly flowing day
Frolicking in the slowly flowing day
愛してるも通り越して
Beyond even saying "I love you"
似た者同士こうして
Like-minded souls like this
年老いるまで笑っていたいね
I want to keep laughing with you until we grow old
君がいなきゃ lonely lonely day
Without you, it's a lonely, lonely day
夢の中 Fall asleep in bed
In a dream, fall asleep in bed
起こすから morning call で
Because I'll wake you up with a morning call
I'll protect you from nightmares, Baby
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
はい、それではですね、皆さん、これ聞いていただきまして
Alright, so everyone, thank you so much for listening to this,
本当にありがとうございます。
I truly appreciate it.
こんなにしっとり歌わせていただいたんですけども、
I sang it so softly like that,
バラードなかなか、3Dライブでやらないので、
but since I don't usually do ballads in 3D lives,
すごく緊張しました。どうだったでしょうか？
I was really nervous. How was it?
あ、めっちゃ拍手と、めっちゃいいってやつが見える。ありがとうございます。
Oh, I see so much applause and comments saying "so good". Thank you so much.
そして、ここでお待ちかねのあの告知を挟ませていただければと思います。
And now, I'd like to make that long-awaited announcement.
それでは元気に行きます。それではドン！
Alright, let's do this with energy. Here we go!
風真いろは誕生日記念 2025 グッズ発売！イエーイ！
Kazama Iroha's 2025 Birthday Memorial Goods are coming! Yay!
ビジュアルが大変よろしい！
The visuals are excellent!
こちらのグッズが販売決定です。
These goods are now available for sale.
はい、というわけで詳細を見ていきましょう。ドン！
Alright, let's take a look at the details. Bam!
回転アクリルスタンド
Rotatable Acrylic Stand
はい、まず一つ目は回転アクリルスタンド。イラストはNardack先生に描いていただきました。うわー！
Alright, first up is the Rotatable Acrylic Stand. The illustration was drawn by Nardack-sensei. Wow!
こちらですね、あの、こういうことです。あの、裏表になってるって言いたい。
This one is, well, it's like this. I mean, it's double-sided.
裏、裏表になってる。そう、あの、カラーライズ衣装とこの新しい新衣装で裏表になってます。
Double-sided. Yes, it has the Colorize costume and this new costume on the front and back.
くるくる回せるので、あの、ござるのこと回して遊んでください。よろしくお願いします。
It can be rotated, so please play around by spinning me. Thank you.
温感湯呑
Thermo-sensitive Yunomi (Teacup)
そして、次がこちら。はい、温感湯呑。
And next is this. Yes, the Thermo-sensitive Yunomi.
これついさっきサンプルが控え室に届いて試しました。
A sample just arrived in the waiting room a moment ago and I tried it out.
あの、ちゃんとあったかいの入れるとふわーってですね、ちゃんとポコ部が浮き出て
When you put hot liquid in it, the "Poko-bu" logo softly appears,
ござるが打ち合わせとかね、あの、リハやってる間に湯が冷めきってちゃんと緑に戻っておりました。
and while I was in a meeting or rehearsal, the water cooled down and it properly returned to green.
こちらもすごく可愛くてお寿司屋さんとかにあるサイズなのかな、結構大きめのしっかりした湯呑です。
This is also very cute and it's probably the size you'd find in a sushi shop, a fairly large and solid teacup.
ぜひね、使ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
I hope you'll use it.
いろはぬいぐるみ ポップダンス衣装ver.
Iroha Plushie (Pop Dance Costume ver.)
はい、そして次がこちら。はい、風真いろは、新、こちらポップダンス衣装って名前なんですけど、の、ぬいぐるみです！
Alright, and next is this. Yes, it's a plushie of Kazama Iroha in her new... this one is called the "Pop Dance Costume"!
ぜひお迎えしてほしいな。ござるさんのぬいぐるみでみんな遊んでくれ、っていうことで。
I hope you'll welcome it into your home. Everyone, please play with my plushie.
このツインテールのね、新衣装、なんとぬいぐるみになりました。
This twin-tailed new costume has actually been made into a plushie.
あの、手持ちじゃなくて、こう、こういうタイプだったかな、だと思うので、ぜひね、みんなのお家に飾ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
It's not the handheld type, but I think it's this kind of type, so please display it in your home.
おそろいネックレス
Matching Necklace
そして次はこちら。はい、なんとござるのこれ、これとお揃いのこれが出ます。
And next is this. Yes, actually, this one I'm wearing... a matching version of this is coming out.
ちょ、ちょっと待って。もう一回言い直していい？これとお揃いのネックレスが出ます！
Oh, wait a second. Can I say that again? A necklace matching this one will be released!
はい。普段ね、アクセサリーとかつけない隊士さんも、あ、つけないよ、っていう方も、
Even for the fans who don't usually wear accessories, or those who say they won't,
まあよかったらこちらね、あのさっきのぬいぐるみにあのくくって一緒にセットにして飾っていただいたりとか
if you like, you could tie it to the plushie from earlier and display them together as a set,
イベントの時に付けてきてもらえたら嬉しいです。オシャレです。
or wear it to events. It's stylish.
ござると一緒にお揃いに、よかったらしましょう！
Let's match with me if you like!
誕生日記念フルセット
Birthday Memorial Full Set
というわけで、そしてフルセットがこんな感じ。うわー！なんだか爽やかですね。
And so, the full set looks like this. Wow! It feels somewhat refreshing.
そう、ライブタイトルの通りリバーシブルなんでね、いろいろちょっと反転反転がついてたりします。
Yes, just like the live title "Reversible", it has various reversible elements.
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
そして購入特典はこちら。この戦争を終わらせに来ました。
And here is the purchase bonus. I've come to end this war.
今回はですね、グッズが2種類出るということで、数量限定はせずに、ちょっと変わった特典にしてみました。
This time, since there are two types of goods, I didn't limit the quantity and made it a slightly different bonus.
こちらは裏表のタロットカードが付いてきます。
It comes with a double-sided tarot card.
片面にはね、風真の、えっと複製サインとメッセージが入っております。
One side has my reproduced signature and a message.
こちらもこう、裏表で楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです。
I'd be happy if you enjoy both sides.
数量限定とかではないのでゆっくりね、あの...
It's not limited quantity, so please take your time...
よろしくお願いできればと思います。
I hope for your support.
販売開始時間がこの後21時なんですですけど...
The sales start time is at 21:00 after this, but...
ちょっと生配信の関係上...
Due to the livestream...
...ちょっと生配信伸びる可能性の方が今大なので...
...there's a high possibility it'll run over...
生配信中に皆さん、あの、カート見に行ってください。
So please go check the cart during the stream.
あ、でもあの数量限定とかない、ので安心してください。
Oh, but it's not limited quantity, so don't worry.
はい、そしてフルセットの特典もうひとつあります。こちらです。
Yes, and there's one more full set bonus. Here it is.
はい、みんな大好きホロカのカードが1枚付いてきます！
Yes, it comes with one HoloKa card that everyone loves!
はい、皆さんよかったらお手にとって...
Yes, everyone, please pick it up...
...ホロカ勢の皆さんは使ってくださいね。
...and use it if you play HoloKa.
遊び方とか、あとカードの詳細は...
For how to play and card details...
...ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームの公式HPにてご確認ください。
...please check the Hololive Official Card Game website.
よし、今台本めっちゃ見た。言えなかったらやばいと思って。
Alright, I really looked at the script just now.
そしてこちら、一緒に入れさせていただくカードは...
And please note that the card included...
...日本語版のみとなっておりますのでご了承ください。
...will only be in Japanese.
はい、カートのオープンですがこちら、100万人記念グッズと...
The cart opening includes both 1 million sub...
...誕生日記念グッズ両方同時なので皆さんよろしくお願いします。
...and birthday merch at once, so please check it out.
ちょっとごめんなさい生配信押しちゃってごめんね。
I'm sorry for pushing the stream back a bit.
ホロメンも、ホロメンも配信をしてすみません。
And sorry to the Holo members who are also streaming.
はい、というわけでお水飲みます。
Alright, I'll have some water.
はい。というわけで、あと最後のお知らせとしまして...
Alright. So, for the final announcement...
この後、本編終了次第ちょっとまた時間がね、確定じゃ...
After the main stream ends... the time isn't set yet...
...15分からか20分からかどっちかになると思うんですけど...
...maybe 15 or 20 minutes after...
風真いろはのメンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもございますので...
There'll be an encore live exclusive to my membership...
みんなが見たかったあの曲やこの曲を...
I'll be singing and dancing to songs...
...歌ったり踊ったりしますので...
...you've all wanted to see...
よかったら見に来てください。よろしくお願いします。
So please come watch if you'd like. Thank you.
メンバーシップギフトとか今日から入ってくださった隊士さんもありがとうございます。
And thank you to those who gifted or joined today.
はい。そして、なんと残念なことに次の曲が皆さん、
And unfortunately, everyone...
このライブ最後の曲となります。
...the next song will be the last song of this live.
皆さん、もう最後は何を歌うかある程度予想されている方も多いかと思いますが...
Many of you probably have some idea of what I'll sing...
改めて、この度は風真いろは生誕ライブ2025、
Once again, thank you so much for coming...
お越しくださいまして、本当にありがとうございました。
...to Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2025.
そして、あの、制作のために一生懸命頑張ってくださった...
And thank you to the staff, dance instructors...
...スタッフさんや、ダンスの先生やマネージャーさんや、
...managers, and all the creators...
皆さん、クリエイターの皆さんもありがとうございました。
...who worked so hard on this production.
正直、いろいろあった昨年の年末から、
To be honest, after everything late last year...
ここまで声が戻ってライブができるっていうことが、ほぼ奇跡。
...it's a miracle that my voice has returned for this.
なんだったら、もう半分諦めかけていたんですけども...
In fact, I had almost half-given up...
スタッフの皆さんや、ファンの隊士さんたちが、すごい支えてくださって、
The staff and all the fans supported me so much...
いろんな方に支えられて本日、実施することができました。
...and thanks to that support, I could hold this today.
本当にありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
正直まだまだ、本調子じゃない部分が多いのは、正直なところです。
To be honest, I'm still not at my best in many ways.
だけど、今日少しでもこのライブを見て、
But I hope that by watching this live today...
たくさんの人に元気が一人でも多く届いていればなと思っております。
...energy has reached as many people as possible.
これからもリハビリしながらですが、精一杯頑張って参りますので、
I'll continue to do my best while in rehab...
皆さんこれからもよろしくお願いします。
...so I look forward to your continued support.
はい。というわけで、最後の曲に相応しいこの曲。
Alright. This song is perfect for the finale.
皆さん最後に聴いてください。
Everyone, please listen to the last song.
風真いろは、新オリ曲。『君にしか読めない手紙』。
Kazama Iroha's new original song: 'A Letter Only You Can Read'.
ありがとう　書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you"
毎日になっちゃうくらい
It would be every day
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings, which are too heavy
最後に伝えるね
I'll tell you at the end
拝啓　私を形作った君へ
Dear you, who shaped me
相も変わらず言葉を届け続けています
I continue to deliver words as always
拝啓　未来で私待ってる君へ
Dear you, waiting for me in the future
響く音に憂いなどなくお過ごしでしょうか
Are you spending time without any sorrow?
不安が無い日なんて多分無かったけど
There probably wasn't a day without anxiety
私の言葉　君の言葉　重なって笑えたんだ
Our words overlapped and we could laugh
ありがとう　書くとしたら
If I were to write "thank you"
毎日になっちゃうくらい　重すぎる
It would be every day. Too heavy...
...重すぎる
...too heavy.
私の想いは
My feelings...
最後に伝えるね
...I'll tell you at the end.
君がいる
You being here,
それだけでさ
just that alone
理由になるなんて奇跡
becoming a reason is a miracle.
ありがとう
A simple 'thank you'
足りないの誤魔化すよ
isn't enough, so I'll cover it up.
愛してる
I love you.
魔法石のブレスレット
A bracelet of magic stones,
シロツメクサの女王様
the queen of white clover.
ふざけだらけの宝石箱でずっと
In a jewelry box full of playful fun,
遊べるよ君と
I can play with you forever.
思い出のかけらたち
Fragments of memories,
溢れるこの場所で
in this place where they overflow.
私の言葉　君の言葉
My words and your words,
重ねて笑ってたい
I want to layer them and keep laughing.
忘れられる世界で今
In a world that can be forgotten, right now,
私が選んだ生き方
the way of life I've chosen...
手紙をさ　書いたから
I wrote a letter,
この音に乗せて
and I'm putting it into this sound.
ありがとう書くとしたら
If I were to write out my thanks,
毎日になっちゃうくらい
it would happen every single day.
重すぎる私の想いは
My feelings are a little too heavy,
最後に伝えるね
so I'll tell you at the very end.
君がいるそれだけでさ
Just because you are here,
理由になるなんて奇跡
it's a miracle it becomes a reason.
ありがとう足りないの誤魔化すよ
'Thank you' isn't enough, so I'll cover it up.
愛してる
I love you.
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
風真いろは
Kazama Iroha
100万人記念
1 Million Milestone
7月1日
July 1st
MV公開
MV Release
風真いろは 100万人記念「君にしか読めない手紙」 7月1日 MV公開
Kazama Iroha 1 Million Milestone "A Letter Only You Can Read" July 1st MV Release